Guide to the Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) Records, 2008-2020 UA.31.13.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) records
2008-2020
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades
UA.31.13.0007
0.25 Linear Feet
2 Megabytes
Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) is a volunteer student organization that offers free English as a Second Language (ESL) classes to Hispanic adults in the Durham area, and organizes social and educational events for the Latino community in Durham. The Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) records include annual printed and digital scrapbooks, which detail the group's activities for the previous year and include testimonials for the group's work by the student tutors and the tutees, as well as captures of the group's website from 2014-2015.
Historical note
Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) is a volunteer student organization that offers free English as a Second Language (ESL) classes to Hispanic adults in the Durham area, and organizes social and educational events for the Latino community in Durham. GANO offers free classes twice a week on Duke University's East Campus, provides free childcare and parking during class times, hosts regular weekly potluck dinners, and organizes additional events including movie nights, computer and internet training, and weekend activities in Durham. Duke University students volunteer as tutors, childcare providers, and organizers.
Collection Overview
The Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) records include annual printed and digital scrapbooks, which detail the group's activities for the previous year and include testimonials for the group's work by the student tutors and the tutees. Also included are captures of the group's website from 2014-2015.
Provenance
The Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO) records were received by the University Archives as a gift in 2015-2020.
Access Restrictions
Access note. Collection contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Related Materials
Office of Continuing Studies Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Student Organizations Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Community Service Center Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Volunteers for Youth, Duke University Chapter Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Office of Student Activities and Facilities Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers; Student service -- North Carolina; Adult education; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc; Gente Aprendiendo para Nuevas Oportunidades
- Scrapbooks
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access note. Collection contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Scrapbook, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, April 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 2014-2015 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 2015-2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 2017-2018 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, 2019-2020; 1 document (PDF); approximately 2 MB (Digital-materials UA.31.13.0007-SET-0001)
    Access note. Contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
    Scope and Contents
    Includes GANO's annual scrapbook in a digital format.
- Web Archives
  - Web Archives, 2014-2015